+1 (215) 252-6186 | mail@vidurbhatnagar.com | www.vidurbhatnagar.com

Product Management | Strategy | Innovation

SUMMARY

Technical product manager, with a successful record of delivering enterprise products, including at my own Healthcare startup. Experienced in customer discovery, analytics, UI/UX, crafting product vision/strategy and leading cross-functional teams through ideation, development & launch.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SLALOM LLC

Product Management Lead

JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

First hire in a new team established to develop SaaS products at a consulting firm and help global teams scale delivery.

- Led a cross-functional team of 5 to **launch a new sales intelligence tool across 5 markets** while conducting user interviews and translating business requirements to technical features.
- Architected the solution for Slalom's largest philanthropic engagement (in a team of 6 selected across 300 applicants)

KERITON LLC

Founder & CEO MAR 2016 - AUG 2018

Launched Keriton while pursuing MS in Robotics at UPenn (on a hackathon winning idea) to help moms, nurses and lactation consultants achieve better outcomes for babies by automating breastmilk management. Eventually, took a leave of absence to run the company full-time as I was granted **extraordinary skills status** by the US government (O1 Visa, EB1 Green Card).

- As an early stage founder, I donned several hats to lead the 10-person organization to a \$10M enterprise valuation
- Raised \$100K in the first 30-days, and another \$1M in the next 6-months from top-tier VCs.
- Conducted design thinking sessions with 25 nurses and interviewed 350+ moms to map business processes and launch a
 2-app system (for moms and nursing staff). This end-to-end breastmilk management automation prevented \$2.5M worth of
 HIPAA-errors at a single site, decreased expiration of milk by 50% and reduced time spent on milk management by
 50%.
- Crafted exceptional user experiences such as the world's first lactation analytics platform with real-time chat for timely intervention and photo-sharing to provide the right stimuli to moms, **helping moms' increase their pumping by 40**%.
- Designed the brand guidelines including **UI mockups for 40+ screens**, company website, decks, one-pagers, flyers, etc.
- Managed the technology team and architected the SaaS platform 2 apps, 4 products, 40+ workflows, 60+ database tables/views, and 80+ APIs with **zero downtime in 1.5 years** with 99.99% SLAs.
- Closed \$1.1M worth of multi-year B2B contracts, created pre-sales collateral and conducted sales demos.
- Coordinated multiple go-live activities at customers' end, and in one instance trained **150+ nurses in 2 weeks**.
- Organically generated 30+ news articles and launched a newsletter for 10,000+ recipients, resulting in top SEO results.
- Pitched at numerous events to win **14 national and international awards** like Gold Stevie Startup of the Year, America's Most Unique Small Business, Impact Pediatric SXSW Pitch Competition, etc.
- As the Chairman of the Board, I conducted quarterly board meetings and implemented effective internal controls

SAP LABS INDIA

Product Owner & Software Engineer

FEB 2013 - JUL 2015

• As the **Youngest Product Owner (globally)**, I led the charge on enterprise visualizations & dashboards for SAP Cloud for Planning and SAP Lumira. I was responsible for defining roadmaps, building cross-functional consensus, and delivery.

- Selected as a Technical Fellow in the Managing Director's office where I developed API services, SQL scripts, and predictive algorithms on SAP HANA for Moneyball for Cricket (SAP Sports Analytics). Using our solution, Kolkata Knight Riders, a Cricket franchisee in India, won back to back championships in 2014.
- Created user stories and conducted customer workshops as a Product Management Fellow for SAP Palo Alto team for Stanford's Social Flex Seating - a group-ticketing app.
- Researched a novel algorithm for SAP HANA to optimize compression algorithms using statistical estimation and demonstrated an improvement of 75-100% on data access speeds. I was awarded as the Employee of the Year (across 4500 employees in India) in 2013 for this project.

ROHITS & CO. (INDIA)

Freelance Software Engineer

JUL 2011 - JAN 2013

Designed and delivered a tool to automate revenue cycle management for SMBs, bringing down the manual process time from 30 days to 30 mins.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

2015 - 2016

Candidate for MS in Robotics (Major – Artificial Intelligence)

GPA - 4.0 (on 4)

3 awards at PennApps - world's largest hackathon - 2nd Prize (2015), 2nd Prize (2016), Best Entrepreneurial Hack (2016)

JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

2008 - 2013

Dual Degree BS (Computer Science) & MBA (HR)

MBA GPA - 8.9 | BS GPA - 8.5 (on 10)

- Government of India scholarship for academic excellence (for 5 years from 2008 2013)
- 2nd rank (out of 150)

SKILLS

- Product Management (Customer Discovery, Feature Prioritization, Roadmaps, GTM and Pricing Strategies)
- Full-Stack Development & Cloud Architecture (Java, JS, SQL, AngularJS, Ionic, Cordova, React, NodeJS, Git, AWS)
- Data & Analytics (Python, Tableau, PowerBI)
- Sales & Marketing (Streak, Zoho, Hubspot, MailChimp)
- UI/UX (Photoshop, Inkscape)
- Exceptional interpersonal and communication (written, verbal and presentation) skills
- Strong problem solving, negotiating, conflict resolution and decision-making skills

PATENTS & PUBLICATIONS

 Visualization of Key Performance Indicator Dependencies (US) Jun 2017 (Issued)

• Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (US/EU) Apr 2016 (Issued)

Virtual Split Dictionary for Search Optimization (US)

Dec 2015 (Issued) Jun 2016 (Filed) • Improved Expression of Breastmilk via Automated Methods (US)

Multi-Dimensional Visual Analytics for Industries (US/India) Sep 2015 (Filed)

• In-Memory DB Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (IEEE CCEM 2015) Nov 2015 (Published)

 A Cost-Effective Sign Language to Voice Emulation System (IEEE IC3 2015) Aug 2015 (Published)